Finding Aid for Bright Sheng Papers, 1962-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Moving Images
  - DVDs
    - Performances
      - Madame Mao Act I (Opera in Two Act), July 27, 2003
        - DVD for PC
Since 1998, Bright Sheng has been the Artistic Advisor to the highly regarded " Silk Road Project," an international program that identifies, archives, and interprets musical traditions of the Far Eastern trade route. In 2002, Sheng was Director of the Festival of Contemporary Music at Tanglewood. He has also served as composer-in-residence for the Art Institute of Chicago (April 2003); the Brevard Music Festival (June 2003 and June 2004); the Winnipeg New Music Festival (2001); co-Artistic Director (with Gerard Schwarz) of the Seattle Symphony's "Pacific Rim" Festival (2001); Artistic Director of the San Francisco Symphony's "Wet Ink 93" Festival; and Composer-in-Residence with the Santa Fe Chamber Music Festival (1993). From 1992 to 1995, he was the resident composer with the Seattle Symphony. Bright Sheng currently serves as a featured composer and performer at the Pacific Symphony's 2004 Chinese American Composers Festival. His chamber music will be highlighted at the Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center, as they present their commissioned work Concerto for Clarinet and String Quartet as part of society's 35th anniversary season.
As a scholar, Sheng has published a number of articles. These include Melodic Migration along the Silk Road-Northwest China (2002); The Love Songs of Qinghai (1995) published by Asian Art & Culture, Sackler Gallery, Smithsonian Institution; Bartok, the Chinese Composer (1998), published by Freer Gallery, Smithsonian Institution; H'un (Lacerations): in Memoriam 1966-1976 for Orchestra (1995) by Perspectives of New Music; Leonard Bernstein: Portrait of the Artist by a Young Man (1989) by Ear Magazine of New Music. Sheng has also undertaken translations of Brahms' Ein Deutsches Requiem, from German to Chinese, in 1996, as well as an adaptation from Danish into English, in 2003, of Hans Christian Andersen's story The Phoenix for his own lyric adaptation.
Sheng has taught at the University of Michigan since 1995. His courses have included: Composition, Graduate Seminar in Composition, Undergraduate Seminar in Composition, Orchestration I (Theory 371), Advanced Orchestration (Theory 471), Creative Composition (Composition 421), Advanced Orchestration (Theory 471), and Turning Points (a cross-disciplinary course with faculty from Department of English and School of Arts). During summers, he has served as guest conductor and composer giving concerts and master classes at Bowdoin Summer Music Festival, Tanglewood Music Center, Brevard Music Center, and Atlantic Center for the Arts. In the summers of 1992 through 1994, he taught at the Young Composer Workshops with the Seattle Symphony Orchestra. During 1994-1995, Bright Sheng taught at the University of Washington, where he offered courses entitled Composition, Composition Seminar, 20th Century Counterpoint, and Advanced Theory.
Sheng has given numerous lectures in many universities including:
Princeton University (1992)
Harvard University (1994)
University of Chicago (1992-1996)
Northwestern University (1991-92)
City University of New York (1988-98)
University of Pennsylvania (1998-99)
University of Minnesota (1990)
University of Pittsburgh (2000)
Indiana University (1999)
University of Cincinnati (1995-02)
Duquesne University (2000)
University of Maryland (1991)
University of California at Los Angeles (1994)
Carnegie Mellon University (2000)
University of Iowa (1993)
University of Colorado (1993)
University of Kansas (1994)
University of Hawaii (1998)
De Paul University (1992)
Ohio State University (2002
University of Ohio at Bowling Green (1988-03)
The Julliard School, NY (1993-00)
Curtis Institute, PA (2001-03)
New England Conservatory, ME (1990)
Cleveland Institute, OH (1996-98)
Peabody Conservatory, MA (1991)
Mannes College of Music, NYC (1999-03)
St. Mary's College, ME (1997).
Bright Sheng's music is published exclusively by G. Schirmer. As a conductor and pianist, he is represented worldwide by Columbia Artists Management (www.cami.com). His discography includes recordings on the Sony Classical, BIS, Delos, Koch International, New World, and Naxos labels.